<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ruby on My Point of View</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tags/ruby/</link><description>Recent content in ruby on My Point of View</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 17:50:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Built a Ruby Parser</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/i-built-a-ruby-parser/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 17:50:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/i-built-a-ruby-parser/</guid><description>Sorry, this post will read like a &amp;ldquo;dear diary&amp;rdquo; entry rather than some life-changing HN-worthy guidance.
Back in November 2020, almost on a whim I started work on a new parser for the Ruby programming language. It was almost exactly a year after I had started working on my compiler project (I hope to write a longer post about that someday soon), and in my frustration with the state of affairs with Ruby parsers available to a humble C/C++ programmer, I decided to see how hard it would be.</description></item><item><title>Clipboard History in Sway Window Manager</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/clipboard-history-in-sway-window-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 21:07:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/clipboard-history-in-sway-window-manager/</guid><description>Recently I switched to the Sway window manager on my favorite laptop and realized that ClipIt does not work there. I was reminded of an old Ruby script I wrote way back in 2012 to serve this purpose.
Time to dust that thing off and make it work with Wayland! I installed the excellent wl-clipboard by Sergey Bugaev and started hacking.
Here is my script:
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to use it:</description></item><item><title>Dymo Printer Agent for Linux</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/dymo-printer-agent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 21:55:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/dymo-printer-agent/</guid><description>Note: We no longer use this. I have an updated post for the new setup.
Our church uses iPads and Dymo printers for children check-in. Parents check in their child, a label prints on the printer, and they stick the label on the child&amp;rsquo;s shirt. We use Planning Center Check-ins of course, and it&amp;rsquo;s great!
One downside to Dymo printers, however, is that their software only runs on Mac and Windows, necessitating a full computer connected to the printer.</description></item><item><title>Find photos on your hard drive to upload to Flickr.</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/find-photos-on-your-hard-drive-to-upload-to-flickr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/find-photos-on-your-hard-drive-to-upload-to-flickr/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you have thousands of photos on Flickr, and thousands more scattered accross your laptop, external drive, and phone.
What&amp;rsquo;s been uploaded to Flickr and what hasn&amp;rsquo;t? Who knows!
I hacked up a quick solution in Ruby and called it Flickr Upload Set.
It&amp;rsquo;s built as a web app with Sinatra, but it&amp;rsquo;s not meant to run on a server &amp;ndash; just on your local computer.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:</description></item><item><title>What is Quality?</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/what-is-quality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/what-is-quality/</guid><description>A lightning talk (5-minute) presentation I gave at TulsaWebDevs:
What is Quality
Note: I used to have this presentation embedded here, but it was scrolling the page and interfering, so now it&amp;rsquo;s just a link.</description></item></channel></rss>