<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Point of View</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/</link><description>Recent content on My Point of View</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:20:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mpov.timmorgan.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/about/</guid><description>Hi! 👋
My name is Tim. I like to create stuff.
You can follow me on the birdsite. Indeed, I have left Twitter at least once, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m back. :-) In the day I work for a company called Planning Center, which builds really great software for churches. At night and on weekends I like to tinker with things that bend my mind, such as compilers and algorithm challenges.</description></item><item><title>Using a Raspberry Pi as a Planning Center Check-Ins Printer Station</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/using-a-raspberry-pi-as-a-planning-center-check-ins-printer-station/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:20:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/using-a-raspberry-pi-as-a-planning-center-check-ins-printer-station/</guid><description>First, some background 🔗My church uses Planning Center Check-Ins to track attendance for churchgoers, and to help with security with little ones going to kids areas. It&amp;rsquo;s a great product. Yay!
Check-Ins runs on iOS, Android, macOS, and Windows machines. Yay!
Dymo label printers are cheap and plentiful. Yay!
Check-Ins can print to a Dymo printer from macOS or Windows, but not from a tablet. Boo!
The problem 🔗We want to print to Dymo printers, which are inexpensive, from an iPad.</description></item><item><title>I Built a Lisp Compiler</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/i-built-a-lisp-compiler/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:10:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/i-built-a-lisp-compiler/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m very proud to announce the completion of my first programming language compiler!
Malcc is an incremental and ahead-of-time lisp compiler written in C.
This is the story of my progress over the years and what I learned in the process. An alternate title for this post is: &amp;ldquo;How to Write a Compiler in Ten Years or Less&amp;rdquo;
(There&amp;rsquo;s a TL;DR at the bottom if you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the backstory.</description></item><item><title>Clipboard History in Sway Window Manager</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/clipboard-history-in-sway-window-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 21:07:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/clipboard-history-in-sway-window-manager/</guid><description>Recently I switched to the Sway window manager on my favorite laptop and realized that ClipIt does not work there. I was reminded of an old Ruby script I wrote way back in 2012 to serve this purpose.
Time to dust that thing off and make it work with Wayland! I installed the excellent wl-clipboard by Sergey Bugaev and started hacking.
Here is my script:
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to use it:</description></item><item><title>Church.IO</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/church.io/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 20:27:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/church.io/</guid><description>Recently I made the decision to shut down the church.io website (it&amp;rsquo;s now a redirect), delete the corresponding Slack community, and move the GitHub repositories back to my own personal account. Church.IO failed to build the community of software creators I dreamed of.
Mistakes were made. This is a retrospective, and an explanation for anyone wondering where we went.
What Was it? 🔗&amp;ldquo;Church.IO&amp;rdquo; was created in 2011, intended to be a lovely little community of developers and designers who code and craft open source software specifically for churches.</description></item><item><title>Leaving Twitter</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/leaving-twitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 21:41:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/leaving-twitter/</guid><description>Late in 2017, I politely said good-bye to Twitter and deleted my account. My Twitter account was 10 years old, and the anniversary, as anniversaries often do, prompted me to think about the value of a decade spent microblogging.
I remember when Twitter was a quiet site for geeks, and my first tweets were about HTTP servers and Git and SliceHost (remember them?). And my geek friends replied sometimes. And there were no politics.</description></item><item><title>Dymo Printer Agent for Linux</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/dymo-printer-agent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 21:55:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/dymo-printer-agent/</guid><description>Note: We no longer use this. I have an updated post for the new setup.
Our church uses iPads and Dymo printers for children check-in. Parents check in their child, a label prints on the printer, and they stick the label on the child&amp;rsquo;s shirt. We use Planning Center Check-ins of course, and it&amp;rsquo;s great!
One downside to Dymo printers, however, is that their software only runs on Mac and Windows, necessitating a full computer connected to the printer.</description></item><item><title>Authority on Rails (Gem for Declaring User Authorization)</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/authority-on-rails-gem-for-declaring-user-authorization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/authority-on-rails-gem-for-declaring-user-authorization/</guid><description>CanCan is a wonderful plugin for Rails that allows you to define all your authorization logic in one place. For small apps, it works well. But as my app&amp;rsquo;s authorization needs grew more complex, I realized I needed a different approach to declaring and testing authorization.
So I went looking&amp;hellip; It turns out that the Authority gem is exactly what I was looking for:
Authority splits out auth logic into individual &amp;ldquo;Authorizers&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Find photos on your hard drive to upload to Flickr.</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/find-photos-on-your-hard-drive-to-upload-to-flickr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/find-photos-on-your-hard-drive-to-upload-to-flickr/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you have thousands of photos on Flickr, and thousands more scattered accross your laptop, external drive, and phone.
What&amp;rsquo;s been uploaded to Flickr and what hasn&amp;rsquo;t? Who knows!
I hacked up a quick solution in Ruby and called it Flickr Upload Set.
It&amp;rsquo;s built as a web app with Sinatra, but it&amp;rsquo;s not meant to run on a server &amp;ndash; just on your local computer.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:</description></item><item><title>What is Quality?</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/what-is-quality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/what-is-quality/</guid><description>A lightning talk (5-minute) presentation I gave at TulsaWebDevs:
What is Quality
Note: I used to have this presentation embedded here, but it was scrolling the page and interfering, so now it&amp;rsquo;s just a link.</description></item><item><title>JavaScript Gotchas</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/javascript-gotchas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/javascript-gotchas/</guid><description>Here are some common time sinks encountered when building a JavaScript app, along with some tips to avoid them.
Note: these tips were originally shared as a part of my TulsaWebDevs presentation following 2012 Startup Weekend Tulsa.
Bind 🔗In JavaScript, scope is resolved during a function&amp;rsquo;s execution &amp;ndash; not its definition. When working with classes, you expect that this will point to the class, but it often won&amp;rsquo;t.
Example:
var Todo = Backbone.</description></item><item><title>Migrate Posterous Blog to Jekyll</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/migrate-posterous-blog-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/migrate-posterous-blog-to-jekyll/</guid><description>Posterous is set to shut down on April 30th. For the past month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreading the move from Posterous to whatever.
Today I bit the bullet and decided to migrate my Posterous blog to Jekyll. There are many reasons I chose Jekyll &amp;ndash; independence from free hosted services is probably the biggest reason.
I chose to use Octopress, which extends Jekyll with a set of sane defaults and a good structure for customizing layout, CSS, etc.</description></item><item><title>Super simple clipboard history for Linux.</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/super-simple-clipboard-history-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/super-simple-clipboard-history-for-linux/</guid><description>I recently switched from Gnome to i3 on my main laptop. So far, I'm enjoying the simplicity of piecing together my own desktop environment from small, specialized tools.
One thing I missed from Gnome was my clipboard history tool, Gpaste. I've come to expect that my previous dozen or more clipboard copies are a keystroke or two away and not lost forever.
While tweaking my i3 setup, I realized it would be possible to replicate some or even all of the functionality of GPaste using simple unix tools:</description></item><item><title>Hacking Well Underway</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/hacking-well-underway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/hacking-well-underway/</guid><description>The Tulsa Hackathon is steaming ahead. The night is still young!
People have gone from standing to sitting, staring intently at backlit screens and making things happen.
Here are some more pics&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Midnight and Still Hacking</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/midnight-and-still-hacking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/midnight-and-still-hacking/</guid><description>More pics!</description></item><item><title>Tulsa Hackathon Kick-off</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tulsa-hackathon-kick-off/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tulsa-hackathon-kick-off/</guid><description>So far the Tulsa Hackathon, an all-night programming drive benefiting needy Tulsa non-profits, is going underway and going well.
We had an excellent catered meal, project presentations were made, and teams have been formed. People seem to be figuring out team member responsibilities and getting started on the various projects.
I&amp;rsquo;ll write a couple more blog posts as the night progresses. Here are pics thus far:</description></item><item><title>Robots Chatting With Other Robots</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/robots-chatting-with-other-robots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/robots-chatting-with-other-robots/</guid><description>I wanted my own Campfire-style web chat room, so I created on with node.js and socket.io that runs on Heroku. Robot images are thanks to robohash.org. Enjoy. github.com/seven1m/robots-chatting-with-other-robots</description></item><item><title>New Blog About Church Software</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/new-blog-about-church-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/new-blog-about-church-software/</guid><description>Oh Good Lord in heaven, forgive me: I've started a new blog.Many of you know I've long had a passion for churches and the software they use. I have plans to challenge the notion of what good church software should be doing. I have ideas for making better tools to aid management, shepherding and engagement. I want desperately to sit down and just start hacking on a new product, but the older and wiser part of me (I did just turn 30 this year, you know) understands that I should have a plan, or at least, you know, a clue about what I'm going to do.</description></item><item><title>jQuery Template Attribute Language</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/jquery-template-attribute-language/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/jquery-template-attribute-language/</guid><description>Introducing jqtal, my tiny jQuery plugin that provides a different way of doing client side HTML templating.
jqtal is different because it is a part of and lives alongside the HTML itself. An example might help:
The plugin uses HTML5 data- attributes to embed data necessary for content insertion. Whereas in a normal template language, you might have something like:&amp;lt;input name="first_name" value="{{ person.first_name }}"/&amp;gt;...in jqtal, you do this instead:&amp;lt;input name="first_name" data-val="</description></item><item><title>Backbone.js Talk at TulsaWebDevs May Meeting</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/backbonejs-talk-at-tulsawebdevs-may-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/backbonejs-talk-at-tulsawebdevs-may-meeting/</guid><description>Hey friends, I wanted to let you know I will be giving a presentation on Backbone.js at the next TulsaWebDevs meet-up.
For any of you using more than the tiniest amount of JavaScript in your web-based applications, Backbone.js may be something to consider. Backbone brings structure and organization to the client-side that we've long had in MVC frameworks on the server. Here are some benefits:Stores data in specialized data "models" instead of directly on the DOM.</description></item><item><title>Red Dirt Ruby Conference II</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/red-dirt-ruby-conference-ii/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/red-dirt-ruby-conference-ii/</guid><description>Red Dirt Ruby Conference in nearby Oklahoma City was even better this year than last year, and that&amp;rsquo;s saying a lot.
The format of RDRC is unlike any other conference I&amp;rsquo;ve attended. The key difference: each speaker (excepting keynote speakers) only talks for 18 minutes and that&amp;rsquo;s it.
Speakers are grouped, four at a time, into a theme. This year&amp;rsquo;s themes (for day one, which is all I was able to attend) were Ruby Implementations, Rails 3 Extensions, Rails Redux, and JavaScript.</description></item><item><title>Auto-Compile SASS with Jammit</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/auto-compile-sass-with-jammit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/auto-compile-sass-with-jammit/</guid><description>I won&amp;rsquo;t bother explaining to my regular readers what these two things are. If you need this, then you know&amp;hellip; ;-)
I know that both SASS and Compass can be setup to &amp;ldquo;watch&amp;rdquo; a directory and auto-compile when files are changed, but it seemed a waste to me to have another thing I have to remember to launch.
This hack piggybacks on Jammit&amp;rsquo;s include_stylesheets helper method and compiles and .scss files in the public/stylesheets directory if they&amp;rsquo;ve changed since last time.</description></item><item><title>David Brady Screencast with James Edward Gray II</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/david-brady-screencast-with-james-edward-gray/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/david-brady-screencast-with-james-edward-gray/</guid><description>Just got done watching this excellent discussion of Ruby hashes, associative arrays, testing, and Ruby culture.Link. James is an excellent force of enlightenment and encouragement in our little community, and I'm proud that he's also an Okie. Go watch this video.</description></item><item><title>Hanlon's razor</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/hanlons-razor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/hanlons-razor/</guid><description>Never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by stupidity.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon's_razor</description></item><item><title>EC2 = Everything Cleared 2Day (FIXED)</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ec2-everything-cleared-2day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ec2-everything-cleared-2day/</guid><description>I created a free micro instance on Amazon EC2 a few weeks ago. Today I remembered it and thought I would tinker around a little, only to find out that when I logged into AWS console, I had to "re-activate" my account using a phone number.&amp;nbsp;Hmmm, that's weird. I distinctly remember doing that two weeks ago.&amp;nbsp;So I jumped through the hoops and got logged in again to discover that my instance was gone, my security group was gone, and my elastic ip was gone.</description></item><item><title>Winexe on Ubuntu</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/winexe-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/winexe-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>If you're running a Linux desktop in an otherwise Windows environment, winexe may be something you'll enjoy.Winexe allows you to execute commands from a Linux machine on a remote Windows machine, as if you're sitting at the Windows command prompt. Think of the possibilities!
Recently, I found a way to get it to compile on my beloved Ubuntu Maverick (it broke when I dist-upgraded for some reason), and I thought I'd share.</description></item><item><title>Use a Proc with ActiveRecords' default_scope Method</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/use-a-proc-with-activerecords-defaultscope-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/use-a-proc-with-activerecords-defaultscope-me/</guid><description>Today, my small patch to Rails was applied by the core team. This is only my second contribution to Rails, so I&amp;rsquo;m fairly stoked about it being accepted.
This will allow you to pass a block to the default_scope method in ActiveRecord. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like much, but opens up some wonderful possibilities.
First, a review of what default_scope does:
The first call to Person.all applies the default scope and adds a where clause that returns only non-deleted folks.</description></item><item><title>Use rsync instead of cp</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/use-rsync-instead-of-cp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/use-rsync-instead-of-cp/</guid><description>I tend to use rsync when others would typically use a simple cp for copying files. A few reasons:
It can be canceled in the middle, and resumed later. It can show a progress bar that (while not perfect) is great for large files or lots of files. It will only copy the changed files and won&amp;rsquo;t clobber already existing directories of files at the target. rsync is available on Linux, Mac, and there&amp;rsquo;s a binary somewhere on teh intarwebs for Windows.</description></item><item><title>Red Dirt Ruby Conf</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/red-dirt-ruby-conf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/red-dirt-ruby-conf/</guid><description>Just some pics. :-)</description></item><item><title>MBP Upgrade</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/mbp-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/mbp-upgrade/</guid><description>My 1st generation Macbook Pro is starting to show its age, but tonight I used my birthday money in an effort at rejuvenation.
First, a new Seagate hard drive. 500gb, 7200rpm, $99 at Best Buy. It took about an hour to get my machine apart, with all its tiny screws, get the new drive in, and put it back together.
Next, I said good-bye to Mac OS X. I installed the brand new Ubuntu 10.</description></item><item><title>Whiteboard Icons</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/whiteboard-icons/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/whiteboard-icons/</guid><description>Back in 2005, I uploaded a bunch of crude little pictures to my Flickr account [edit 12 years later: this account is gone] and called them my &amp;ldquo;Whiteboard Icons&amp;rdquo; set. Hundreds of people have, over the years, found them to be useful on their blogs, flowcharts, and more.
Today, I finally added a couple new icons to the set. Only took me five years.
Enjoy.
Update: Various sizes and scalable versions are available in the whiteboard_icons git repository.</description></item><item><title>csv2wufoo.com</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/csv2wufoocom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/csv2wufoocom/</guid><description>csv2wufoo.com is a little side project I wrote using Sinatra, my WufooParty lib, and James Edward Gray's FasterCSV lib. After the tenth time my wife asked me to write a one-off script to import data into her Wufoo form, I decided to generalize it a bit, slap a Sinatra app around it, and give it a domain name (well, there was a little more to it than that, but ya know&amp;hellip;) It hasn't quite been battle tested yet, but hopefully it will be useful to someone.</description></item><item><title>FacebookParty</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/facebookparty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/facebookparty/</guid><description>I wanted to understand the Facebook REST API better, and decided I needed a simple wrapper for it. HTTParty to the rescue again!FacebookParty (rdoc) is along the same lines as my other _party style api wrappers. I can't take much credit for it though, since HTTParty is what makes this stuff so easy. Slap a pretty class on an api endpoint, and the rest is cake. And cake goes good with parties.</description></item><item><title>Updated Tarsnap Activity Graphs (Greasemonkey Script)</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/updated-tarsnap-activity-graphs-greasemonkey-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/updated-tarsnap-activity-graphs-greasemonkey-script/</guid><description>I just updated my Greasemonkey userscript that generates usage graphs for Tarsnap. The graphs are now prettier: The script lives here.</description></item><item><title>Flickr API for Ruby Using HTTParty</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/flickr-api-for-ruby-using-httparty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/flickr-api-for-ruby-using-httparty/</guid><description>Continuing with my HTTParty, I've created a fairly simple Flickr API wrapper for Ruby: flickr_party. This one was a bit more difficult than the Campaign Monitor one, but still fun nonetheless.
Why reinvent the wheel?
It's fun.I always learn something.
Sometimes I learn to not reinvent the wheel.But sometimes I learn so much more. The libraries out there I spent 10 minutes looking at didn't seem to fully support application authentication.</description></item><item><title>CampaignMonitor API Wrapper</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/campaignmonitor-api-wrapper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/campaignmonitor-api-wrapper/</guid><description>Update: This was renamed to campaign_monitor_party.
First of all, HTTParty is simply amazing. That is all.Second, Ruby never ceases to amaze me regarding its power and tools for meta-programming. "method_missing" is just too cool. Third, I created a 20-line wrapper class for the Campaign Monitor API this weekend (using HTTParty). The code and the gem is over on GitHub: http://github.com/seven1m/campaign_monitor_party.</description></item><item><title>CascadingRubies - Ruby DSL for generating CSS</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/cascadingrubies-ruby-dsl-for-generating-css/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/cascadingrubies-ruby-dsl-for-generating-css/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a little experiment lately&amp;hellip; a Ruby domain-specific language for generating Cascading Style Sheets called CascadingRubies.
It&amp;rsquo;s an internal DSL, meaning it uses plain Ruby syntax, like this:Output:Being just Ruby, of course, you can mix in variables, arithmetic, require external code, hit the database, or whatever.
The guys on the Tulsa.rb mailing list have provided some great feedback, and from that I&amp;rsquo;ve released the the second gem version (0.</description></item><item><title>Install the Ruby gem "dnssd" on Ubuntu</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/install-the-ruby-gem-dnssd-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/install-the-ruby-gem-dnssd-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>sudo aptitude install libavahi-compat-libdnssd-dev sudo gem install technomancy-dnssd -s http://gems.github.com require &amp;#39;rubygems&amp;#39; require &amp;#39;dnssd&amp;#39;</description></item><item><title>ShrinkSafe with Prototype 1.6</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/shrinksafe-with-prototype-16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/shrinksafe-with-prototype-16/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t find this information anywhere, so here it is for the Google archives&amp;hellip;
To get Prototype to run after squeezing it through ShrinkSafe, you need to put back every instance of the variable $super. ShrinkSafe replaces variable names with shortened versions, and because of some Prototype voodoo, it breaks on this one name. There are about 8 places you&amp;rsquo;ll find it, and unfortunately, it takes some manual hunting once ShrinkSafe has changed a bunch of names, but there you have it.</description></item><item><title>Ditch Pagination</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ditch-pagination/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ditch-pagination/</guid><description>I build web apps. Almost every one has a screen or two somewhere that shows a listing, and at the bottom it has pagination links, e.g. next page, page 3, etc. For a recent app I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, the interface is very search-driven, i.e. the user enters some criteria the results are displayed.
As an experiment, I left off the pagination links. In this app, there is no &amp;ldquo;next page.</description></item><item><title>SliceHost Affiliate Link</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/slicehost-affiliate-link/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/slicehost-affiliate-link/</guid><description>Just posting this for any friends getting ready to sign up for a SliceHost account. This my referral link - I get a discount on my slices if you use this. Help a poor developer, please.https://manage.slicehost.com/customers/new?referrer=198350528</description></item><item><title>Tulsa Ruby Workshop</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tulsa-ruby-workshop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tulsa-ruby-workshop/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re gearing up for the upcoming, very first Tulsa Ruby Workshop.Of course, all you need to know is on the website, but in short, it&amp;rsquo;s a beginner&amp;rsquo;s conference all about Ruby and Rails. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Ruby and/or Rails, this is for you (if you&amp;rsquo;re in or near enough to Tulsa, Oklahoma that is). Tell everyone you know!</description></item><item><title>FireFox 3 Beta</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/firefox-3-beta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/firefox-3-beta/</guid><description>Oooo I really like the new Firefox 3 beta. It&amp;rsquo;s zippy and it looks great.My only beef was the new fancy address bar&amp;hellip; Being an uber web geek, I tend to recognize things by their URLs instead of page titles, so this was slowing me down to much:So, to get things back all barebones FF2 style, I installed this and set browser.urlbar.matchOnlyTyped in about:config to true. Much better.</description></item><item><title>OneBody: Using Git</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/onebody-using-git/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/onebody-using-git/</guid><description>I still plan on writing the final part in the Git series on this blog, but in the meantime, on a related note, we now have a page up on the OneBody wiki about Using Git. It includes some instructions for using Git on Windows and some other commands that may be helpful to noobs.</description></item><item><title>Rails Routes Weirdness</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/rails-routes-weirdness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/rails-routes-weirdness/</guid><description>Just to save you a half-hour of your life, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share that you should never create a named route called &amp;ldquo;directory&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; it will break Rails migrations and other rake tasks in mysterious and hard-to-track-down ways.</description></item><item><title>Git For People Who Know Svn, Part 2</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/git-for-people-who-know-svn-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/git-for-people-who-know-svn-part-2/</guid><description>For Part 2 of our 60-second Git tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at some super simple branching and merging.
git branch tells you which branch you&amp;rsquo;re on.
git branch -a lists all branches, even remote ones.
git checkout mybranch checks out the branch you want.
git checkout -b newbranch creates a new branch from the one you&amp;rsquo;re on, and checks it out for you.
git checkout master &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git merge mybranch merges changes from one branch to your master branch.</description></item><item><title>Git For People Who Know Svn (Things I've Learned, Part 1)</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/git-for-people-who-know-svn-things-ive-learne/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/git-for-people-who-know-svn-things-ive-learne/</guid><description>First, the mental hurdles:You don&amp;rsquo;t need a server to have a git repository. All your commit history is available locally and quickly, with simple commands. Same with branches and tags. Git &amp;ldquo;checkout&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;commit&amp;rdquo; are commands you run locally. Svn &amp;ldquo;checkout&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;commit&amp;rdquo; are really more like &amp;ldquo;pull&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; with git.
Now, the commands:
rails myapp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd myapp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git init &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git add . &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit -a creates a repo and makes the first commit (but still nothing is sent to any server; all work is done locally in your own repository)</description></item><item><title>Advanced Ruby on Rails</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/advanced-ruby-on-rails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/advanced-ruby-on-rails/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the book Advanced Rails by Brad Ediger. I first met Brad way back in 2006 when we were first trying to get our local Ruby user group going. He is a very smart fellow, and his newest book is definitely evidence of that. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot in there that&amp;rsquo;s over my head, but that&amp;rsquo;s nothing a few rereads can&amp;rsquo;t solve. :-)The book has everything from optimization to deployment, from security to metaprogramming (my brain is still spinning from that one).</description></item><item><title>OneBody Blog</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/onebody-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/onebody-blog/</guid><description>OneBody now has a real, bona fide blog of its own. Thanks to WordPress.com, creating a new blog is waaaay too easy, evidenced by the fact that I now have 37 (just kidding).
Our little project continues to grow and improve. I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting on that influx of talented, eager volunteers to make it awesome, though :-) For now, it will continue to be Tim&amp;rsquo;s pet project, though I refuse to stop referring to the development &amp;ldquo;team&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;us.</description></item><item><title>Backup Your Gmail Account Messages With Ubuntu and Fetchmail</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/backup-your-gmail-account-messages-with-ubunt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/backup-your-gmail-account-messages-with-ubunt/</guid><description>Long title, I know. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it&amp;hellip;
sudo apt-get install fetchmail postfix cd ~ vim .fetchmailrc Add the following to the file (replacing everything in CAPS appropriately):
poll pop.gmail.com with proto POP3 and options no dns user &amp;#39;YOUR_GMAIL_ADDRESS&amp;#39; there with password &amp;#39;YOUR_PASSWORD&amp;#39; is &amp;#39;YOUR_UBUNTU_USERNAME&amp;#39; here options ssl Now:
chmod 710 .fetchmailrc sudo vim /etc/crontab Add the following to your crontab file:
10 7 * * 1 YOUR_UBUNTU_USERNAME fetchmail -k This will run fetchmail every Sunday and grab your email.</description></item><item><title>Google Search Everywhere &lt;em>Except&lt;/em> a Site</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/google-search-everywhere-except-a-site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/google-search-everywhere-except-a-site/</guid><description>Just saw this in my referrer logs&amp;hellip; You can search on Google for all occurrences except in a certain site.
Many know about adding site:timmorgan.org or similar to only search within a certain domain. Well, maybe it was obvious, but now I know you can do -site:timmorgan.org to search everywhere but that domain. Nice.</description></item><item><title>Social Networking for Your Church</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/social-networking-for-your-church/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/social-networking-for-your-church/</guid><description>Starting around mid- to late-2006, I started a little project for my church. The idea was to rewrite our existing online membership directory to make it more searchable and to take a stab at creating something somewhat social, where people can easily communicate with each other and also see their interests and such. Plus, I was dying to build something significant with Ruby on Rails, my new favorite web framework.</description></item><item><title>mpov.timmorgan.org</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/mpovtimmorganorg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/mpovtimmorganorg/</guid><description>I used Wordpress.com&amp;rsquo;s nifty domain mapping feature and moved my blog to its own domain. Now, after I write that killer blog post that gains me tons of Google juice, I can use my newfound popularity to redesign my blog with AdSense and make beaucoups of money. /dream</description></item><item><title>The New Gmail</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/the-new-gmail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/the-new-gmail/</guid><description>It seems the Gmail team has quietly slipped in a minor upgrade to the revolutionary and still yet after more than 3 years, best web email system I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. I have to use Outlook at work and yearn for the day that it will properly thread replies as Gmail does, but I digress&amp;hellip;
Anyway, is it just me, or is the slightly &amp;ldquo;improved&amp;rdquo; Gmail actually dumber? Here are some pet peeves I&amp;rsquo;ve aquired in the last week of using the new Gmail: For one, the drop down menus (you know, for selecting an action on individual and/or selected email) are no longer real select lists; they&amp;rsquo;re instead some DHTML kind of thing that has a scroll bar that feels flimsy.</description></item><item><title>Find &amp;amp; Replace in Word with Ruby</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/find-andamp-replace-in-word-with-ruby/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/find-andamp-replace-in-word-with-ruby/</guid><description>You can script Microsoft Word using COM and the Ruby win32ole library.
First, create a plain Word document with text to replace like this:
Here is some text of my document. This will be replaced with [name]. Today&amp;rsquo;s date is: [date].
Then, run the following code. The text in square brackets will be replaced with the values in the code, and the file will be saved as a new name.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu 7.10 Rocks</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ubuntu-710-rocks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ubuntu-710-rocks/</guid><description>The new Ubuntu rocks, let me tell you. For one reason: things just work. This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever installed a Linux OS and didn&amp;rsquo;t have to crack open the terminal to tweak XOrg settings or to manually install graphics drivers, etc. My wireless card worked, upgrading my graphics drivers was as simple as a few clicks in the GUI, and turning on Compiz effects was as a dream.</description></item><item><title>Politics and 18-30 Year-Olds</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/politics-and-18-30-year-olds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/politics-and-18-30-year-olds/</guid><description>There seems to be a general dissatisfaction with politics amongst people my age. We have a bad taste in our mouths. We&amp;rsquo;ve grown up watching a political process that seems to only happen on our TVs. And we feel we have absolutely no power to influence it. Because it&amp;rsquo;s a one-way channel.
In some ways, the whole process is like a bad television show.
The things we learned in grade school and high school (at a time when we were too young to participate) made the system seem beautifully complex and perfectly designed.</description></item><item><title>Ron Paul</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ron-paul-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ron-paul-17/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing a lot on the Web about this guy named Ron Paul. He&amp;rsquo;s running for president in 2008, but first he has to get the Republican nomination. He has many supporters already, and I only see that growing over the next several months.
Ron Paul is the only politician I&amp;rsquo;ve read about who truly fights for individual rights and follows the constitution. He&amp;rsquo;s restored my hope for the country and for the Republican party.</description></item><item><title>One (Spotty) Year of MPOV</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/one-spotty-year-of-mpov/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/one-spotty-year-of-mpov/</guid><description>I just realized I&amp;rsquo;ve now had this blog for one year. While its postings have been sporadic at times, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to look back on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done tech-wise over the last year.
FYI: Anyone who reads this blog may be interested to know that I can be found posting useless things all over teh Interwebs (not just here), many of which you can find at timmorgan.org or on my brand new Jaiku account (timmorgan.</description></item><item><title>Zooomr</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/zooomr-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/zooomr-1/</guid><description>Zooomr is a little photo sharing site that has a wee bit of potential I think. While I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t exactly call it &amp;ldquo;reliable&amp;rdquo; at the moment (its recent upgrade took it down for weeks and it&amp;rsquo;s service has been sketchy ever since), I could see it amassing a cult following among geeks like myself.
I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting on an API key so I can test my Flickr migration script. I wrote a bit of Ruby to download each of my Flickr photos, along with their tags, geotags, description, title, etc.</description></item><item><title>wget to the rescue</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/wget-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/wget-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>Have you ever been downloading something very large for a long time, and something happens to interrupt it? Firefox crashes, you lose power, you accidentally close your laptop lid, etc.? Here&amp;rsquo;s a trick to start your download where you left off: On Linux, you can skip this step. On Mac, download wget here, unzip it, and put &amp;ldquo;wget&amp;rdquo; in /usr/bin. For Windows, looks like you can download wget here (I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried this on Windows, but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be much different).</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia Watchlist Feed v2</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/wikipedia-watchlist-feed-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/wikipedia-watchlist-feed-v2/</guid><description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this for awhile now, and I still have to manually check my watchlist every day because my reader only gets updates every few days. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure, but it seems to be a caching issue on the WP API and not so much the script&amp;rsquo;s fault.Update 2: The load on my server was too much, so I removed the hosted script from my server. You can still download the source and host it yourself.</description></item><item><title>Snippets Feed</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/snippets-feed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/snippets-feed/</guid><description>It occured to me that my gems of wisdom on my Snippets page likely go unnoticed by you faithful blog readers, so you might want to subscribe to my snippets feed as well so you don&amp;rsquo;t miss beauties like this (yes, I know this will seem lame to some, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s clever):
class Object def in?(object) object.include? self end end 1.in? 2..3 #=&amp;gt; false 1.in? 1..3 #=&amp;gt; true</description></item><item><title>Lost is Finding Itself Again</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/lost-is-finding-itself-again/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/lost-is-finding-itself-again/</guid><description>My guess is Lost has lost many of its viewers in the last year due to a crawling storyline and endless questions without answers. I say this because, after watching tonight&amp;rsquo;s episode, the direction of the show has definitely changed. I think those writers finally figured out they don&amp;rsquo;t have blind followers &amp;ndash; they have to get off their butts and actually move the story along. And that&amp;rsquo;s what they finally did tonight.</description></item><item><title>Music Sharing</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/music-sharing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/music-sharing/</guid><description>Dvorak is spot on about the music industry: During the heyday of Napster and open free music sharing and trading, when million of people swapped songs, the CD business was booming. Once Napster was shut down, and along with it the social network of music discovery, sales began to plummet. They are still falling.</description></item><item><title>Useless Account</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/useless-account/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/useless-account/</guid><description>This is my reason for getting one:You're addicted to signing up to account-requiring websites the moment they're released just so no one else takes your usual username.</description></item><item><title>Preacher Blog</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/preacher-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/preacher-blog/</guid><description>Greg Pittman, the preaching minister at my church, now has a blog. I got him set up this weekend, and he&amp;rsquo;s started it off with a great post about our recent prayer week.
He also said something interesting to me that really got me thinking about how the Web has affected us the last few years:I&amp;rsquo;m not looking to be trendy. It [blogging] just seems to be an effective way to communicate with an ever-ambiguous, mobile congregation, and in a more interactive fashion.</description></item><item><title>CRCC Website Overhaul</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/crcc-website-overhaul/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/crcc-website-overhaul/</guid><description>As we tend to do every couple years, Jennie and I have once again overhauled the website of Cedar Ridge Christian Church, our church home in Broken Arrow, OK. I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of this one. It has a clean look but seems modern enough to not look like your run-of-the-mill church website.</description></item><item><title>How to get more views on your Flickr photos</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/how-to-get-more-views-on-your-flickr-photos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/how-to-get-more-views-on-your-flickr-photos/</guid><description>&amp;hellip;
Tag them with the word &amp;ldquo;breast.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not kidding. I uploaded some crappy photos from our breastfeeding class two weeks ago; one has six times more views and other has over 25 times more views than all my other crappy photos. Just goes to show that for most people, the Internet is for porn.</description></item><item><title>(Probably) Worse Than Crack</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/probably-worse-than-crack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/probably-worse-than-crack/</guid><description>Not that I would really know, but I&amp;rsquo;d imagine hard drugs couldn&amp;rsquo;t be much more addictive than Facebook. I&amp;rsquo;m still sinking my roots deep into that thing, finding more and more old friends and people I forgot about (sorry; bad memory :-).
Particularly, I hope to find more college and high school friends and see what they&amp;rsquo;re up to these days.</description></item><item><title>Hpy</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/hpy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/hpy/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m still running Hpy, a place to list things that make you happy. I still think the idea is simple and neat, though it has yet to reach critical mass. Go see my list here and think about adding your own.</description></item><item><title>Server Migration</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/server-migration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/server-migration/</guid><description>I host a few low-traffic websites out of my house. One of them is actually a paying customer! The last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on migrating all my web apps/sites to a new server (still at my house). This time, though, I spent some time on the infrastructure to make things more reliable. I set up RAID 1 mirroring on my hard drives. I also utilized VMWare Server (free) and built a virtual server image.</description></item><item><title>Ruby Website Redesign</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ruby-website-redesign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ruby-website-redesign/</guid><description>My favorite programming language had a bit of a facelift. Now the homepage is as beautiful and elegant as the language itself.</description></item><item><title>ZiddlyWiki Lives On!</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ziddlywiki-lives-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ziddlywiki-lives-on/</guid><description>Jeremy Ruston and Bob McElrath have taken over development of ZiddlyWiki. This is amazing &amp;ndash; to see the community value something I worked on for a big chunk of my life and desire that it continue on without me. It&amp;rsquo;s humbling and edifying at the same time! I wish them the best and hope they can take ZW places I never dreamed of.</description></item><item><title>Web 2.0 Logo</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/web-20-logo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/web-20-logo/</guid><description>All those Web 2.0 logos are starting to look the same&amp;hellip; so some guy went and created an app that generates them automatically&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Code Snippet Comments RSS Feed</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/code-snippet-comments-rss-feed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/code-snippet-comments-rss-feed/</guid><description>In my quest to make everything into a feed&amp;hellip; I present the Code Snippet Comments feed. It goes with this site, which lacks a feed for comments posted on snippets.
For this feed generation, I used a free service called Feed43. It&amp;rsquo;s quite powerful! Basically, you give it a URL and about ten minutes of your life working out some pattern recognition, and voila! you get a feed auto generated every six hours based on the content of the page.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia Watchlist RSS Feed</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/wikipedia-watchlist-rss-feed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/wikipedia-watchlist-rss-feed/</guid><description>Update: Version 2 is available here.Today, I finally got fed up with Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s lack of watchlist feeds, so I wrote a script that generates them.
A few of the photos I had uploaded to the Wikimedia Commons have been marked for deletion for some time now due to inadequate license information (my fault entirely), but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it because I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about the Commons having its own separate watchlist.</description></item><item><title>Lightbox with Iframes</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/lightbox-with-iframes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/lightbox-with-iframes/</guid><description>I needed a version of Lightbox that handled real web page urls instead of just images, so I hacked it myself. I looked into using Lightbox Gone Wild, but it seemed a misnomer; it&amp;rsquo;s more like a stripped down version of Lightbox. I like the effects and transitions of Lightbox, so I figured why not start there?I&amp;rsquo;d love to show you an example, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a host for it right now.</description></item><item><title>Rush-Hour Ethics</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/rush-hour-ethics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/rush-hour-ethics/</guid><description>Here's a phenomenon that really peeves me. On my way home every weekday, I pass South through these two intersections. During rush-hour, traffic can get quite backed up here, so the wait can easily be ten or fifteen minutes at this one point in my drive home. What&amp;rsquo;s worse is that people cheat. As the second map below shows, people take a side road over to Peoria, turn South, then line up at the same intersection, but in a much shorter line.</description></item><item><title>ZiddlyWiki</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ziddlywiki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ziddlywiki/</guid><description>Update: The community has stepped up to take over development of ZiddlyWiki. So, it appears ZW will live on!
Update 11/7/2007: Ziddlywiki.com has been dead for a long time now. I really like TiddlyWiki and think there should be a solid server implementation like ZW was; make your plea in a comment on this post if you'd like to discuss a ZW comeback.
ZiddlyWiki was a product I built and maintained for awhile.</description></item><item><title>Mac Bragging</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/mac-bragging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/mac-bragging/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually done anything with the new Mac, but I&amp;rsquo;ve sure had fun doing it! I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit swamped with work lately, so my bandwidth for additional projects is near zero. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to install all the geeky Mac tools and surf the web a lot.
Oh, and I worked last night to get all my photos (over 30GB worth!) in one place (on the Mac) so I can start sorting and archiving and such.</description></item><item><title>New Mac</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/new-mac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/new-mac/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post from my brand spanking new MacBook Pro. Man O Man is this thing a piece of work. It&amp;rsquo;s simply beautiful. It feels solid, yet lightweight. It&amp;rsquo;s screen is absolutely flawless and can be seen surprizingly well from all angles. The keyboard illumination feature is kick-butt. Typing at night will never be the same (yes I know how to type, but doing programming requires a lot of arrow keys and symbols, and I can&amp;rsquo;t always find those in the dark).</description></item><item><title>Switchers</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/switchers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/switchers/</guid><description>Seems everybody who&amp;rsquo;s anybody these days is &amp;ldquo;switching&amp;rdquo; from one platform to another. Mark Pilgrim switched from Mac to Linux. Jamie Zawinski switched from Linux to Mac. Josh Marshall switched from Windows to Mac. And, well, I can&amp;rsquo;t think of anyone prominent who switched to Windows, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure everybody&amp;rsquo;s drooling over Vista.
My point is, over the last two years, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt less and less like a &amp;ldquo;switcher&amp;rdquo; and more like a tool collector.</description></item><item><title>Stephen and Tim Day</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/stephen-and-tim-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/stephen-and-tim-day/</guid><description>Today was officially proclaimed "Stephen and Tim day" because of all our work lately on integrating our systems with the state of Oklahoma.</description></item><item><title>The Team</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/the-team-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/the-team-3/</guid><description>My coworker Joseph put this together. I think it's awesome. See more here.</description></item><item><title>Sucker</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/sucker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/sucker/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s official: I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker.
I got an iPod for my birthday two months ago. And I love(d) it. I&amp;rsquo;ve become addicted to a handful of podcasts over the past few months and my collection of music has been slowly growing. My car radio has largely forgotten the sound of traditional broadcast radio.Yesterday, my iPod booted up with this icon. I took it back to Best Buy to get it exchanged, only to find out the extra fifty bucks spent on &amp;ldquo;extended service&amp;rdquo; or whatever they called it means they ship the iPod back to Apple for repair instead of making me do it.</description></item><item><title>Junk Email Filter Dot Com</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/junk-email-filter-dot-com/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/junk-email-filter-dot-com/</guid><description>We just started using an email filtering service at Cedar Ridge. So far, I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased with it. In the two days it&amp;rsquo;s been in place, only a handful of spam messages have passed through to our server, and every one of those were filtered by our existing DNS blacklist filtering.
The filter works by proxy, meaning all mail destined for our domain is first delivered to junkemailfilter.com. Their server filters out the spam using some fancy voodoo and delivers the good stuff to our server.</description></item><item><title>Less Spam</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/less-spam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/less-spam/</guid><description>I have an ongoing experiment in which I never empty my Spam folder in Gmail. On the left side of the screen, when I log in, I can see how many spam messages I have. Gmail automatically deletes spam messages over thirty days old, so this is an accurate representation of how many spam messages I get in a given thirty-day period.When I first started using Gmail, my spam folder grew quickly to contain over five hundred spam messages!</description></item><item><title>Python Rehab Clinic, Part I</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/python-rehab-clinic-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/python-rehab-clinic-part-i/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many people are switching from Python to Ruby these days, but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a bit and thought it would be helpful to a few people if I cross-referenced my Python knowledge to my (growing) Ruby knowledge. I got this idea from James on the OK.rb mailing list.
Part One will focus on where to find what in the Ruby community. With any programming language or framework, you have a set of resources you go to often to find what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.</description></item><item><title>What's the Diff?</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/whats-the-diff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/whats-the-diff/</guid><description>Interesting campaign, but surely they're not implying the BSOD only happens on non-pirated Windows software, are they?Speaking of BSOD, how did I ever miss this? Classic.</description></item><item><title>I {Heart} Ruby</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/i-heart-ruby/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/i-heart-ruby/</guid><description>Everyday, I find yet a bit more to love about Ruby&amp;hellip;Hmmm, surely there's a method to update bla bla&amp;hellip;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; some_object.methods.grep /update/=&amp;gt; [&amp;quot;update_attributes&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;after_update&amp;quot;, &amp;hellip;]Sweet!</description></item><item><title>Ten Rails Tips</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ten-rails-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/ten-rails-tips/</guid><description>Here's my Ten Rails Tips, expanded a bit to try to explain my thinking&amp;hellip; Scaffolding won't write your app for you, otherwise DHH would have called it &amp;quot;foundationing&amp;quot;. Too often I see people addicted to the Rails scaffolding feature. I've found that it's often a crutch for actually thinking about the problem at hand. Scaffolding is great for a one-table model, but breaks down quickly when you have has_manys and other such relationships.</description></item><item><title>OK.rb Talk</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/okrb-talk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/okrb-talk/</guid><description>I gave a talk tonight at the quarterly Oklahoma Ruby User Group meeting in Edmond. It was not nearly as difficult nor as boring (for everybody else) as I had feared. In fact, I think many in the room actually enjoyed my talk!Most of it focused on my experiences getting Rails to work on Microsoft IIS. Here is my presentation. And here is my Ten Rails Tips of a Ruby Noobie, which I also shared.</description></item><item><title>More Translations for 43V</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/more-translations-for-43v/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/more-translations-for-43v/</guid><description>43 Verses now offers six translations instead of just one! This required a major overhaul of the code, but now that it's done (bar a few remaining bugs I'm sure), it should be much easier to add other translations later (as they are made available as web services).
I'm still tweaking the UI for working with the translations, so bare with me. Suggestions are welcome.
Later.</description></item><item><title>Tyrannical, Inanimate Meathead</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tyrannical-inanimate-meathead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/tyrannical-inanimate-meathead/</guid><description>From now on, I'd appreciate it if you'd call me by my real name above. To find your true name, check out this site.</description></item><item><title>Daily Bread - Now With Feeds</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/daily-bread-now-with-feeds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/daily-bread-now-with-feeds/</guid><description>43 Verses now offers a few of the verse lists (the recent page and individual users' pages) as feeds so you can keep up with the goings-on from your favorite news reader. I've been using the Google Reader lately, and I'm starting to like it a lot. Even just the ability to star items to find them easily later is a very handy feature.</description></item><item><title>43V Redesign</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43v-redesign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43v-redesign/</guid><description>I finally got around to redesigning 43 Verses a bit :-). I got the design from openwebdesign.org and the bible image from sxc.hu. Let me know if you run into any funkiness (especially in IE).</description></item><item><title>43V in JS</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43v-in-js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43v-in-js/</guid><description>Now you can get your 43 Verses in a format you can stick on your blog or other personal website. Just go to your 43V &amp;quot;My Verses&amp;quot; page and add this to the URL: &amp;quot;?format=js&amp;quot;. If you don't want all your verses listed, you can add another argument called &amp;quot;count&amp;quot; like this: &amp;quot;&amp;amp;count=10&amp;quot;. So the full URL might look like this: http://43verses.com/users/show/1?format=js&amp;amp;count=10You can see an example of this in use at our family weblog.</description></item><item><title>KJV, ASV, YLT, AKJV</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/kjv-asv-ylt-akjv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/kjv-asv-ylt-akjv/</guid><description>There's a web service API for these older translations (all in the public domain). I'm thinking about adding them to 43V. I get chills just imagining the list of available translations growing as more translations are made available as web services. Of course, the big kahuna would be NIV, but I doubt Zondervan would ever make their content freely available. Pay per word, maybe, but never free. That's a shame.</description></item><item><title>My Name in Flickr</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/my-name-in-flickr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/my-name-in-flickr/</guid><description>This app is cool:</description></item><item><title>43V Bookmarklet</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43v-bookmarklet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43v-bookmarklet/</guid><description>Every good Web 2.0 website needs a bookmarklet or three, right? 43V now has a Tools page where I've added a handy bookmarklet that allows you to highlight an on-screen scripture reference and look it up on 43V. Super handy for all those Verse-of-the-day emails you've been getting for the past three years.</description></item><item><title>What's up with that blog title?</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/whats-up-with-that-blog-title/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/whats-up-with-that-blog-title/</guid><description>I wanted to forewarn any readers that this blog is not necessarily politically correct all the time. I don't consider myself a backwards hick, but I do have some decent opinions about some touchy subjects, some of which may come up from time to time. I don't apologize.
I had a blog in the past that served primarily as my outlet for geeky stuff (just as this one is). Occasionally, I'd throw in something about my faith as a Christian and it would invariably tick off someone and I'd get nasty comments.</description></item><item><title>43 Verses and 1 More Blog</title><link>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43-verses-and-1-more-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mpov.timmorgan.org/43-verses-and-1-more-blog/</guid><description>I launched my most recent pet project: 43 Verses.
The idea is simple&amp;hellip; I needed a place to list all those darned bible verses I'm supposed to be remembering. Well, turns out I have a horible memory when it comes to this stuff, so why not make another Web app to do the work for me?
Less than a day after the launch of 43V, I got an email from a long-time blog reader offering to host the thing on his reseller account (thanks again, Mike).</description></item></channel></rss>